Guide to the Fernando Alegria Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series 2. Manuscripts by Alegria
  - Alegria, Fernando. La poesia chilena en el Siglo XX: Cecilia Vicuña (1948): tms, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - Alegria, Fernando. La poesia chilena en el Siglo XX: Alicia Galaz Vivar: tms, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - Alegria, Fernando. La poesia chilena en el Siglo XX: Veronica Zondek (1953): tms, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - Alegria, Fernando. La poesia de Jorge Boccanera. -- In Excelsior 1981 July 28 (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - Alegria, Fernando. El poeta y el Postino: tms, n.d., 8 p. (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Posse: los perros del paraiso: tms, n.d., 13 p. (Box 22, Folder 37)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Las preguntas de Neruda: tms, n.d., 15 p. (Box 22, Folder 38)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Premio de literatura - Casa de Chile: tms, n.d., 4 p. (Box 22, Folder 39)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Prologo: tms, n.d., 2 p. (Box 22, Folder 40)
  - Alegria, Fernando. La prosa de Gabriela Mistral: tms, ca. 1987 (Box 22, Folder 41)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Proyecto de reforma de la canción de Yungay: tms, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 42)
  - Alegria, Fernando. La puerta del Diablo: clipping. -- In El Diario de Hoy 1973 June 17 (Box 22, Folder 43)
  - Alegria, Fernando. La rebelión de los placeres: Borradores: tms, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 44)
  - Alegria, Fernando. La rebelión de los placeres: copias y descantados: tms, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 45)
  - Alegria, Fernando. La rebelión de los placeres: tms, 1999 (Box 22, Folder 46)
    Includes rejection letter, 1999
  - Alegria, Fernando. La rebelión de los placeres: treatment, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 47)
  - Alegria, Fernando. La rebelión de los placeres: translation, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Includes tls from Lisa Fetchko, translator.
  - Alegria, Fernando. La rebelión de los placeres: correspondence with Elena Castedo & Elaine Markson, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Recuerdo de Gustavo Ossorio: tms, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Recuerdo de Gustavo Ossorio: tms, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Recurso del método: tms, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Alegria, Fernando. La relacion: Alvar Nuñez Cabeza de Vaca: tms, n.d., 2 copies (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Reminiscences and critical reflections. -- p. 61-68. -- In Modern Critical View: Pablo Neruda. -- New York: Chelsea House, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Alegria, Fernando. [Reseñas]: tms, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Retrato de familia: tms, n.d., 4 p. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Retratos contemporaneos: tms, 1980 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    Mistral, Gabriela Parra, Violeta River, Diego Torres, Camilo
  - Alegria, Fernando. Review of Open Door by Luisa Valenzuela: tms, n.d., 5 p. (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Rolando Alarcon: tms, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Romeria a la memoria de Meza: tms, n.d., 19 p. (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Romulo Gallegos: tms, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Ronda del ausente: tms, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Runrunismo: tms, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Alegria, Fernando. S. Allende: cronologia: tms, n.d., 34 p. (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Salvador Salazar Arrue (1899-1975): tms, ca. 1991 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Los sangarimas [por] J. de la Cuadra: ams, ca. 1934 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Sangre de mestizos [por] Augusto Cespedes: ams, ca. 1936 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Santiago del Nuevo Chileno: tms, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Santiago del Nuevo Chileno: tms with holographic emendments, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Santiago del Nuevo Chileno: tms, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Santiago del Nuevo Chileno: facsimile proof, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Santiago viego: tms, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Alegria, Fernando. La semilla en la sombra: el arte de Pablo Neruda: tms, n.d., 9 p. (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Alegria, Fernando. La semilla en la sombra: el arte de Pablo Neruda (1904-1973): tms, n.d., 21 p. (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Alegria, Fernando. La semilla en la sombra: el arte de Pablo Neruda (1904-1973): tms, n.d., 22 p. (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Sergio Hernandez: ultimas señales: [review]: tms, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Si van para Chile: tms, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Si van para Chile: tms, n.d., 17 p.; 16 p. (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Si van para Chile: tms, n.d., 16 p. (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Si vas para Chile (Chito Faro): ams, n.d., 1 p. (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Si vas para Chile: tms, n.d., 10 p. (Box 23, Folder 34)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Si vas para Chile: tms, n.d., 17 p. (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Si vas para Chile: tms, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 36)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Situación de Chile: ams, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 37)
  - Alegria, Fernando. La soberania y la paz en nuestra America: tms, n.d., 8 p. (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Alegria, Fernando. La soberania y la paz en nuestra America: tms, n.d., 8 p. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Sobre Angel C[?] Santa Maria: holograph ms, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Sor Juana by Octavio Paz: tms, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Souzalo Millan (1947): ams, n.d., 3 l. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Alegria, Fernando. The state and the poet: an art of resistence. -- p. 1-9. -- In Pacific Coast Philology n.d. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Surrealismo en la generación del 38: tms, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Tahoe: el circulo de fuego: tms, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Tahoe: el circulo de fuego: tms, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Tahoe: el circulo de fuego: tms, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Tercer mundo: tms, n.d., 2 p. (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Tercer mundo: tms, n.d., 2 p. (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Teresa Calderón (1955): tms, n.d., 9 p. (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Alegria, Fernando. El tiempo nos silba su tornada: ams, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Tonada de la concientizacion: tms, n.d., 1 p. (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Translating Whitman: tms, ca. 1991 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Alegria, Fernando. A tribute to Sartre: tms, n.d., 2 p. (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Trio: los adioses: tms, n.d., 6 p. (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Ultimo round: tms, n.d., 6 p. (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Victor Jara: tms, n.d., 5 p. (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Violeta Parra: tms, n.d., 10 p. (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Alegria, Fernando. A visit to Borges: tms, n.d., 10 p. (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Visita a Borges: tms, n.d., 11 p. (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Walt Whitman in Hispanic America: tms, n.d., 127 p. (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Walt Whitman in Spain and Latin America: tms, n.d., 41 p. (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Walt Whitman in Spain and Latin America: tms, n.d., 41 p. (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Walt Whitman in Spain and Latin America: tms, n.d., 56 p. (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Walt Whitman in Spain and Latin America: tms, n.d., 57 p. (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Walt Whitman in Spain and Latin America: tms with annotations by Dan Lewis, ed., n.d. (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Walt Whitman in Spanish America: tms: pp. 1-100, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 30)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Walt Whitman in Spanish America: tms: pp. 101-200, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Walt Whitman in Spanish America: tms: pp. 201-300, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Walt Whitman in Spanish America: tms: pp. 301-400, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Walt Whitman in Spanish America: tms: pp. 401-505, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Walt Whitman in Spanish America: tms: pp. 1-120, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Walt Whitman in Spanish America: tms: pp. 121-198, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Walt Whitman in Spanish America: tms: Chapters 3 & 4, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Walt Whitman in Spanish America: tms: section on Pablo Neruda, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Whitman and Neruda: a syllabus: tms, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Whitman: reconciliación (drum-taps): tms, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Alegria, Fernando. War chorale: tms / by Fernando Alegria; trans. by Steven Kessler n.d., 1 v. (68 p.) (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Wars of the words: the politics of the avant garde in Latin America: tms, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Zurzulita [por] M. Latorre: ams, ca. 1920 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Manuscritos en ingles = Manuscripts in English [1 of 2] n.d. (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Manuscritos en ingles = Manuscripts in English [2 of 2] n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Manuscritos - copias - Español = Manuscripts - copias - Spanish [1 of 2] n.d. (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Manuscritos - copias - Español = Manuscripts - copias - Spanish [2 of 2] n.d. (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Discursos Ingles n.d. (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Manuscritos - notas - ficción n.d. (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Ineditos: various tms, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Poesia y notas (traducciones) I n.d. (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled: ams, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled: ams, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled: ams, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled: tms, n.d., 2 p. (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled: tms, n.d., 3 p. (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled: tms, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled: tms, n.d., 2 p. (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled: tms, n.d., 2 p. (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled: tms, n.d., 11 p. (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled tms re: Allende, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled poem: tms, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled tms, "Painters give us works of art ..." n.d. (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled tms, "Painters give us works of art ..." [1 of 2] n.d. (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled tms, "Painters give us works of art ..." [1 of 2] n.d. (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled tms, "Painters give us works of art ..." [2 of 2] n.d. (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled tms, "El velero de tres palos había salido ... " n.d. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled tms, "El velero de tres palos había salido ... ", ver. 2 n.d. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled book: tms [1 of 3] n.d. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled book: tms [2 of 3] n.d. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled book: tms [3 of 3] n.d. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled fragment: tms, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled fragments: tms, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled fragments: tms: pp. 4-9, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled fragments: tms: pp. 5, 8-14, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled fragment: tms, n.d., 1 p. (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled fragment: tms: pp. 20-24, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled fragment: tms, n.d., 1 p. (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled fragment: tms, n.d., 3 p. (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled fragment: tms, n.d., 6 p. (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled fragment: tms: p. 22, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled fragment: tms, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled fragment: tms: pp. 4-9, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled fragment: tms: p. 2, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled fragment: tms: p. 2-11, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled fragment: tms: p. 3, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled fragment: tms: p. 6, n.d., tms with annotations (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled fragment: tms: p. 6-22, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled fragment: tms: p. 7, n.d., tms with annotations (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled fragment: tms: p. 11-13, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled fragment: tms: p. 11-17, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled fragment: tms: p. 16-24, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled fragment: tms, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled fragment: tms, n.d., 1 p. (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Untitled fragments: tms, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 29)
  - [Alegria, Fernando?]. Las persas: tms (photocopy), n.d. (Box 27, Folder 30)
  - [Alegria, Fernando?]. Contra la muerte: los ultimos poemas de Neruda: tms, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 31)
  - Alegria, Fernando. Decalogo de los pastores. -- p. 12-13. -- In Portal. -- No. 5 1967 July (Box 99, Folder 9)
- Series 3. Manuscripts by others
  - Anguita, Eduardo. La visita: tms, 1950 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    Includes biography
  - Aninat, Flor Maria. Fernando Alegria, el escritor chileno que nos visita: tms, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Aninat, Flor Maria. Various tms, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Aponte, Rachel. Various tms, ca. 1995 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Arenas, Braulio. La simple visita: ms with illustrations, ca. 1995 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Ayesa, Guillermo. Bajo tempestados: novela: tms, n.d., 232 p. (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Baeza Flores, Alberto. Tiwanaku: poema. -- (Centro de Investigaciones Arquelogicas, no. 5). -- La Paz: El Centro, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Balcarcel, Jose Luis. Cuba en la conciencia Latinoamericana y el pensamiento de Allende: tms, n.d., 18 p. (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Bandera, Fernando. Lautaro: script adapted from novel: tms, 1998 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Bandera, Fernando. Lautaro: storyboard adapted from novel: tms with illustrations, 1999 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Barrientos, Raul. De Jamaica station: tms, 1997 Mar. 18 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Barrientos, Raul. Lapidario: tms, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Barrientos, Raul. Llave de neón: tms, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Bate, Grecia. Essay B response: tms, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Bate-Campos, Grecia. Nothingness: tms, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Bate-Campos, Grecia. Master's thesis and a collection of monographs: tms, 1988, 1 v. (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Bernales, Jorge. Luis: tms, 1999. -- Fernando: tms, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Bernales, Jorge. Poemas: tms, n.d., 22 p. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Bernales, Jorge. Regreso del gallo: tms, 1991 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Bruce, Lennart. On roses and years: tms, n.d., 4 p. (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Burciaga, Jose Antonio. Juan Rolfo en conversaciones: tms, n.d., 33 p. (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Campos, Jaiver. Los saltimbanquis de la Edad Dorada: novela: tms, 1997, 172 p. (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Campos, Marcia J. Who are the friends of the Indians? -- p. 6. -- In Making tracks, 1995 Dec. (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Cantero, Paola Andrade. Poemas: tms, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Carpentier, Alejo. War of time: tms (photocopy), 1970, 2 copies (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Carrasco, E. Conversación con Matta: tms (photocopy), 1981 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Carrasco M., Ivan. Poesia chilena actual: no solo poetas. -- p. 3-19. -- In Paginadura. -- No. 1 1989 Dec. (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Cassigoli, Armando. Keys to a recognition of Chile: tms, 1981, 28 p. (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Cassigoli, Armando. Soy el dueño de mi propia libertad: cuentos: tms, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Castellanos, Rosario. Album de familia. -- p. 7-22 n.d. (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Cavallari, Hector Marin. Savoir and pouvoir: Michel Foucault's Theory of discursive practice. -- p. 55-72. -- In Humanities and Society. -- Vol. 3, no. 1 1980 Winter (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Chapman, Arnold. Reviews (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Chinchilla, Norma Stoltz. The myth of the passive peasant: the Chilean example: draft tms (photocopy), 1972, 18 p. (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Coelho, Joaquim-Francisco. Carlos Drummond de Andrade e A. Génese do "Sonetilho do Falso Fernando Pessoa". -- p. 63-70. -- In Revista da Biblioteca Nacional. -- No. 1, 1982 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Coelho, Joaquim-Francisco. Da cadeira de Alvaro de Campos. -- In Coloquio / Letras. -- No. 71 1983 (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Coelho, Joaquim-Francisco. Drummond, Primavera, Sombras. -- In Coloquio / Letras. -- No. 47 1979 (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Concha, Jaime. Alain Sicard: la pensee poetique de Pablo Neruda: tms (photocopy), 1977 (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Cox, Barry. Seven brief meditations on César Vallejo and España, aparta de mi este cáliz: tms, 1991 Nov. 29, 38 p. (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - Cox, Barry. Introduction: tms, n.d., 27 p. (Box 29, Folder 23)
  - Dalton, Roque. La Brujula en el bolsillo: tms, n.d., 64 p. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Dalton, Roque. El Mar: p. 7-14 n.d., 7 p. (photocopy) (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - de Carvalho-Neto, Paulo. Chile, cerca de Puas: tms. -- Los Angeles, Calif. 1978, 52 p. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - de la Luz Hurtado, Maria. The construction and reconstruction of Chilean identities: cultural voices from outside and within: tms, 1997 Apr. (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Diaz-Casanueva, Humberto. El canto de conjuro = Song of conjuration 1985 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Diaz-Casanueva, D. Humberto. Sobre el silencio (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Diaz de Vivar, Rodrigo. Guerra entre 2 mundos: tms, 1994 Jan., 30 p. (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Dominguez, Delia. Señales de una poesía mestiza en el parallelo 40 sur 1992 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Duckworth, Penelope. [Poems]: tms, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - El doble y el múltiple en la poesía de Fernando Alegria: tms, ca. 1994 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    Includes card from the author; signature is unreadable.
  - Epple, Juan Armando. Chilenos en California: una trilogía narrativa de Fernando Alegría. -- p. 217-225. -- In the Americas Review. -- Vol. 23, no. 3-4 1995 Fall-Winter (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Epple, Juan Armando. De vuelos y permanencias: tms, n.d., 55 p. (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Epple, Juan Armando. Entrevista: tms, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Epple, Juan Armando. Fernando Alegría: tms, n.d., 39 p. (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Epple, Juan Armando. Fernando Alegría: Salvador Allende, la historia como voluntad de imaginación. -- p. 90-94. -- In Plural. -- No. 228 1990 Sept. (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Epple, Juan Armando. Patricio Manns y la subversión de los modelos de la crónica: tms, n.d., 14 p. (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Epple, Juan Armando. La poetica del desampara: tms. -- p. 89-111. -- In El arte de recordar n.d. (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Epple, Juan Armando. Prologo: tms, n.d., 39 p. (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Epple, Juan Armando. Veintecinco años del grupo Trilce. -- p. 67-80. -- In Paginadura. -- No. 1 1989 Dec. (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Espinosa, Mario Antonio. Beans: a story of Santiago, Chile: tms, n.d., 22 p. (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Espinosa, Mario Antonio. Caida de un angel, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - Espinosa, Mario Antonio. Herencia: tms (photocopy), n.d. (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - Espinosa, Mario Antonio. H.M., n.d. (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - Espinosa, Mario Antonio. Manos a la obra: tms (photocopy), n.d. (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - Espinosa, Mario Antonio. Mario Espinosa, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - Espinosa, Mario Antonio. Una misa en Paris: tms (photocopy), n.d. (Box 30, Folder 26)
  - Espinosa, Mario Antonio. Porotos: tms (photocopy), n.d. (Box 30, Folder 27)
  - Espinosa, Mario Antonio. Reportaje a una momia: tms (photocopy), n.d. (Box 30, Folder 28)
  - Fernandez, M. Elisa. Efforts to manipulate conceptions of national identity in Chile during the 1950's: draft tms, 1995 Mar., 37 p. (Box 30, Folder 29)
  - Fuentes, Pedro. Cuentos de villanos: tms, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Fuentes, Pedro. El vaso de leche: tms (facsimile), n.d. (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Fuenzalida Faivovich, Edmundo. Chile, 1965-1995: modernización cultural e identidad: tms, 1997 Apr. 24-26 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Garcia Antezana, Jorge. Contexto intratextual en Pantaleón y Las visitadores de Mario Vargas Llosa. -- In Actas del Septimo Congreso.... 1980 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Garcia Marquez, Gabriel. Unidentified article n.d. (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Gasser, Manuel. The zoomorphic figures of Fernando Krahn. -- p. 458-463. -- In Graphis n.d. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Gomez, Ulises. Ulises Gomez - Bishop Francis Quinn dialogue: tms (photocopy), n.d. (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Guadalupe de Anda, Jose. Los bragados: novela. -- Mexico: Compañia General Editora, 1942, 1 v. (photocopy) (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Guido, Beatriz. Piedra libre. -- p. 9-20 n.d. (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Heine, Jorge. Countdown for Pinochet: tms, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Hernandez, A.T. Poems: tms (photocopy), n.d. (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Herrera, Ciro. Poemas con direccion: tms, 1995 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Hertz, Uri. Walter Benjamin in Baudelaire's Paris. -- [S.l.: s.n.], n.d., 1 v. (90 p.) (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Hjalstad, Barbara. [Poems]: tms, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Huerta, Alberto. Murieta y los "Californios": Odiseo de una cultura. -- p. 615-649. -- In Religion y Cultura. -- Vol. 29, 1983 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Huidobro, Keith. Vicente Huidobro y La Primera Guerra Mundial. -- p. 333-346. -- In Hispanic Review. -- Vol. 67, no. 3 1999 Summer (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Iffland, James. Hacia una teoria de la función del humor en la poesia revolucionaria (a propósito de Roque Dalton): tms, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Israel, Ricardo. Chile, 1970-1973: Allende and the popular unity: tms, n.d., 13 p. (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Israel Z., Ricardo. Chile before popular unity: tms, n.d., 66 p.; iv p. (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Jiménez, Reynaldo. Realidad y mitificación: tms, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Kirschen, Karen. Violeta Parra: by the whim of the wind: tms, 1993 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Kirschen, Karen. Violeta Parra: by the whim of the wind: tms [1 of 4] ca. 1999 (Box 31, Folder 22)
    Includes als from Violeta Parra to Alegria.
  - Kirschen, Karen. Violeta Parra: by the whim of the wind: tms [2 of 4] ca. 1999 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Kirschen, Karen. Violeta Parra: by the whim of the wind: tms [3 of 4] ca. 1999 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Kirschen, Karen. Violeta Parra: by the whim of the wind: tms [4 of 4] ca. 1999 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Kioski, Linda Irene. Mujeres poetas de Chile: Muestra antologica: tms, 1998 Mar., 1 v. (398 p.) (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Labarca Goddard, Eduardo. Diario de un desaparacido 1979, 1 v. (96 p.) (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Larrain, Luz. La noche del Domingo: tms, 1991 May 5, 1 v. (165 p.) + 1 als (Box 32, Folder 6)
    Includes als from author to Alegria.
  - Lavin [Cerda, Hernan]. Fernando Alegria: entres dos fuegos: tms, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Lindenberger, Herbert. Dogstory: tms, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Lopez, Carlos. Chilean sources for the California Gold Rush: tms, 1970 Spring (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Lopez de Vallarino, Teresa. El gallo Vicente. -- p. 201-211 n.d. (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Lopez U., Carlos. Los chilenos en la fiebre del oro de California: tms, n.d., 16 p. (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Los Presentes: otros poetas n.d. (Box 32, Folder 12)
    Includes poems by Lawrence Ferlinghetti translated by Fernando Alegria.
    Ferlinghetti, Lawrence.
  - Lynch, Marta. Latin lover. -- p. 173-182. -- In Los dedos de la mano. -- Buenos Aires: Editorial Sudamerica, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Manzo, Tom. Untitled tms, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1)